A Finding Aid to the Gertrude Abercrombie papers, circa 1880-1986, bulk 1935-1977, in the Archives of American Art AAA.abergert
Archives of American Art
- Photographs, circa 1880-1978; Series 11; 1 Linear feet Boxes 5-7; OV 8
  Among the photographs of places are interior views of Gertrude Abercrombie's home and studio, unidentified landscapes, travel pictures of San Francisco and commercially produced stereopticon slides of other locations. Miscellaneous subjects are automobiles, cats, exhibition installations, and a still life setup.
  Arrangement note
  Photographs are arranged into 5 subseries:
  Subseries 1: Art Work, 1978, undated
  Subseries 2: People, circa 1880-1976, undated
  Subseries 3: Places, 1958-1971, undated
  Subseries 4: Miscellaneous Subjects, 1931-1961, undated
  Subseries 5: Negatives, Slides, and Transparencies, 1963, undated
  - Art work, 1978, undated; 11.1
    - By Gertrude Abercrombie, 1935-1978, undated (Box 5, Folder 35-36)
    - By Other Artists (works by Karl Priebe, Charles Sebree, and unknown, owned by Gertrude Abercrombie), undated (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - People, circa 1880-1976, undated; 11.2
    - Gertrude Abercrombie (includes portrait by Carl Van Vechten), circa 1909-1970s; ( see also: Box 7; OV 8) (Box 5, Folder 38-44)
    - Gertrude Abercrombie with Groups (including Cameron, Huppler, Sandiford, Priebe, and unidentified), 1953-1960, undated; ( see also: Box 7) (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Gertrude Abercrombie with Groups (unidentified), undated (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Gertrude Abercrombie with Individuals (Alizier, Benjamin, Cameron), 1939-1954, undated (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Gertrude Abercrombie with Individuals (unidentified), 1932-1966, undated; ( see also: Box 7) (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Gertrude Abercrombie and Friends, circa 1945; (26 Photomatic pictures in small metal frames) (Box 5, Folder 49-50)
    - Family (Box 5)
      - Emma Gertrude Stevens Christmas Abercrombie [grandmother], 19th century (Box 5, Folder 51)
      - Joseph Abercrombie [grandfather?], 19th century (Box 5, Folder 52)
      - Tom and Jane Abercrombie [parents] (some views with Gertrude), 19th century-1920s, undated (Box 5, Folder 53)
      - Dinah Livingston [daughter], circa 1942-1960s; ( see also: Box 7) (Box 5, Folder 54)
      - Robert Livingston [first husband] (some views with Gertrude and Dinah), undated (Box 5, Folder 55)
      - Frank Sandiford [second husband] (some views with Gertrude, unidentified individuals, and groups), 1947-1959, undated (Box 5, Folder 56)
      - Mr. and Mrs. James Stevens (Christmas) [great grandparents], 19th century (Box 5, Folder 57)
      - Unidentified Relatives, 19th century-1931, undated (Box 5, Folder 58)
    - Groups (including Don Baum, Arnold Blanch, Lester Bridaham, Dudley Huppler, Doris Lee, and Karl Priebe), 1936-1970, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Groups (unidentified), 1942-1969, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Individuals (Albright-Pearson), 1934-1975, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
      Albright, Ivan le Lorraine
      Burroughs, Margaret
      Chunning
      Gillman, Mack
      Hevish, Jack
      Hupler, Dudley
      Krogh, Whitney
      Mann, Helen
      Meyer, Kenneth
      Meyers, Dick
      Pearson, Albert Raphael
      Purdy, Richard ( see: Box 7)
    - Individuals (Priebe, Karl), 1970, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Individuals (Ruwolo [?]-Woolf), 1942, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
      Ruwolo [?]. Felix
      Tichon, James
      Velde, Rosabelle
      Wilcox, Wendell
      Woolf, Samuel
    - Individuals (Unidentified), 1936-1976, undated; ( see also: OV 8) (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Jazz Artists (Armstrong-Garner), undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
      Armstrong, Louis
      Bigard, Barney
      Catlett, Sidney
      Cooper, Nicholas F.
      Davis, George ( see also: Box 7)
      Garner, Erroll
    - Jazz Artists (Gillsepie, Dizzy; includes portraits by Carl Van Vechten), 1947, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Jazz Artists (Gordon-Washington), 1947, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
      Gordon, Dexter and Melba Liston
      Harris, Bill
      Hawkins, Coleman
      Hines, Earl
      Jackson, David
      Krissly, Swiss
      Liston, Melba ( see: Gordon, Dexter and Melba Liston)
      McGhee, Howard
      Orlando
      Parker, Charlie
      Phillips, Joe "Flip"
      Potter, Tommy
      Roach, Max
      Rollins, Sonny
      Sinatra, Frank
      Thompson, Sonny
      Vaughn, Sarah
      Venturo, Charlie
      Washington, Leon
    - Jazz Artists (unidentified), undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Jazz Artists - Groups (Modern Jazz Quartet), undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Jazz Artists - Groups (including Davis, Harris, Roach, Rollins, Vaughn, unidentified, Gertrude Abercrombie and Frank Sandiford), 1959, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Gertrude Abercrombie, undated; ( see also: Box 5) (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Gertrude Abercrombie with Others (school picture; with unidentified man), circa 1923, undated; ( see also: Box 5) (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Family and Individuals (Dinah Livingston [daughter]; Richard Purdy), undated; ( see also: Box 6) (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Jazz Artists (Davis, George; unidentified), undated; ( see also: Box 6) (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Gertrude (Raphael McPerhson, photographer); Unidentified Man, 19th century; undated (Box OV 8)
  - Places, 1958-1971, undated; 11.3
    - Buildings - Exteriors (home of Gertrude Abercrombie [?]; unidentified), 1958, undated (Box 6, Folder 13-14)
    - Buildings - Interiors (home and studio of Gertrude Abercrombie), 1971, undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Landscapes (unidentified), undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - San Francisco, undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Stereopticon Slides (mainly travel pictures), circa 1880-1900 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous Subjects, 1931-1961, undated; 11.4
    - Automobiles, undated (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Cats, undated; ( see also: Box 7) (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Elephants, undated (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Exhibitions (unidentified group show with self-portrait; "Shells from the Collections of Gertrude Abercrombie", 1931, undated (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Sailboat, "Jolly Molly", 1961 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Still Life Setup, undated (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Cats, undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Negatives, Slides, and Transparencies, 1963, undated; 11.5
    - Art Work (Box 6)
      - Negatives, undated (Box 6, Folder 25)
      - Slides, 1963, undated (Box 6, Folder 26)
      - Transparencies, undated (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - People (Box 6)
      - Negatives, undated (Box 6, Folder 28)
      - Slides, undated (Box 6, Folder 29)
      - Transparencies, undated (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Places (Box 6)
      - Negatives, undated (Box 6, Folder 31)
      - Slide, undated (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Miscellaneous Subjects (negatives), undated (Box 6, Folder 33)